# MICHAEL TUETING

Bodanstrasse 8  $\diamond$  9000 St. Gallen, Switzerland michael.tueting@unisg.ch

#### PERSONAL INFORMATION

Nationality: German

Residence Permits: Switzerland (Aufenthaltsgenehmigung B)

Born: 1996 in Gehrden, Germany

Gender: male Title: M.Sc.

## RESEARCH

My research is in the fields of economic geography, regional economics, and conflict with a focus on developing countries. I am passionate about the spatial distribution of economic activity and people. My research is dedicated to increasing our knowledge of how a country's general spatial equilibrium determines its regions' growth paths.

As a byproduct of my focus on developing countries, I often rely on satellite imagery and historic maps and constantly develop tools for spatial data generation and analysis.

# **EDUCATION**

# University of St.Gallen, Switzerland

Since August 2020

PhD Programme in Economics and Finance

Supervisor: Prof. Dr. Roland Hodler

### Leibniz University Hanover, Germany

October 2015 - July 2020

# M.Sc. with a specialization in Empirical Economics and Econometrics

July 2020

Minor: International Environment and Development Studies

Thesis: "Using Machine Learning to Digitize Maps: An Application to Historical Road Densities in Africa" (Grade: 1.0). Graduated with honors. Final grade: 1.2

# **B.Sc.** Economics and Management

September 2018

Bachelorthesis: "Pre-Colonial Ethnic Homelands and Subnational Borders: The Case of Kenya, Uganda and Tanzania" (Grade: 1.0). Final grade: 2.0

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### RESEARCH ASSISTANCE

SIAW-HSG
Research Assistant
St. Gallen

Institute of Macroeconomics

November 2018 - January 2020 Hanover

Research Assistant

# **TEACHING**

# Master level

Teaching Assistant

· Political Economics (2021-2022)

(University of St.Gallen)

# Bachelor level

Teaching Assistant

· Public Sector Economics (2022) (University of St.Gallen)

· Democratic Choice and Social Welfare (2022) (University of St.Gallen)

· Development Economics (2020-2022) (University of St.Gallen)

· Data Handling: Import, Cleaning and Visualisation (2021-2022) (University of St.Gallen)

· Introduction to Macroeconomics (2017-2019) (Leibniz University Hanover)

· Operations Management (2017) (Leibniz University Hanover)

# **AWARDS**

Dean's List 2018/19 & 2019/20

· Awarded to the best 5% of the study cohort by the Faculty of Economics and Management

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

Statistical Programming R, Python

Geodata GRASS GIS, QGIS, Google Earth Engine, ArcGIS, R, Remote Sensing

Machine Learning Keras, Tensorflow

Tools RStudio, STATA, LATEX